

ABOUT ME

My name is Matthew Callahan and I am a software engineer in Phoenix, Arizona. I have over ten years of experience in web and desktop software development using Scrum, Kanban, and XP agile methodologies. Learning the dynamic landscape of computer programming is my passion.

CONTACT

Email: matthew.callahan@outlook.com

Phone: 630-988-1555

Homepage: mfcallahan.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mfcallahan1

GitHub: github.com/mfcallahan

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Technology Associate: Developer

KEY SKILLS

Languages

C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python

Frameworks

.NET 4.8 & .NET Core 3.1: Web API, Entity Framework, SignalR

Angular 10:

Material, RxJs, NgRx

ArcGIS:

JavaScript API, .NET SDK, Server

Testing

NUnit, Jasmine, Selenium, Cypress

Dev Tools

Git, Azure, Jenkins, Splunk

MATTHEW CALLAHAN

EDUCATION



University of Wisconsin-Madison

Bachelor of Science, Geographic Information Systems

EXPERIENCE

Staff Engineer | Republic Services, Scottsdale, AZ | May 2019 - Present

- Lead a team of eight developers and testers, overseeing talent development, skill set improvement, and acting as a mentor to all team members.
- Established and implemented a standard application architecture for greenfield development (.NET & .NET Core back end/Angular front end).
- Implemented unit test standards for the team and led effort to increase test coverage on all apps, reducing the number of production bugs.
- Authored coding conventions and style guide documents for developers and currently leading effort to refactor all applications to follow these guidelines.
- Technologies used: .NET, .NET Core, C#, Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, SQL Server, ArcGIS.

Sr. Developer | Republic Services, Scottsdale, AZ | Dec 2018 - May 2019

- Developed enterprise GIS web applications which provided data mapping and route visualization tools to assist in business operations (ASP.NET, Angular).
- Developed APIs and services to deliver spatial data to teams and applications throughout the company (ASP.NET Web API).
- Supported desktop application development for GIS data analysis and batch data processing (ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, Python).
- Implemented a uniform Git branching strategy and code review process for all application repositories.

Software Engineer | Carvana, Tempe, AZ | Feb 2018 - Dec 2018

- Primary job function was back end development to create and maintain the APIs and microservices which powered carvana.com (C#, .NET & .NET Core).
- Supported front end development to maintain and enhance a mobile responsive UI for a vehicle inventory search engine (JS ES6+, React/Redux, AngularJS).
- Implemented A/B testing to help drive data analytics and deliver the best UX.

Application Developer | CBRE, Phoenix, AZ | Jan 2011 - Feb 2018

- Developed web applications which provided mapping and site selection data analysis tools for real estate brokers and their clients (ASP.NET MVC).
- Developed desktop applications for GIS data processing and analysis (C# .NET, WinForms, MapBasic, ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, Python).
- Administered on-prem servers (Windows Server, IIS, SQL Server, ArcGIS Server).
- Employee of the year "MVP" award, 2012.

GIS Technician | CBRE, Phoenix, AZ | Mar 2008 - Jan 2011

- Developed scripts and desktop GIS tools to automate tasks and improve workflow efficiency of GIS Technicians.
- Created custom maps, demographic reports, and market research reports for commercial real estate brokers, affording them the ability to make well informed decisions and best serve their clients.
- Employee of the Quarter, 1st guarter 2009.

Resume ver: 2020.07.2